<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <title>Leaves</title>
    <author>Lloyd Schwartz</author>
    <date time="year">- 1941-</date>






    <number>1</number>

    <p n="1">Every <date time="month">October</date> it becomes important, no, necessary to see the
            <nature cat="plant">leaves</nature> turning, to be surrounded by <nature cat="plant"
            >leaves</nature> turning; it's not just the symbolism, to confront in the death of the
        year your death, one blazing farewell appearance, though the irony isn't lost on you that
            <nature cat="word">nature</nature> is most <feeling emotion="intense"
            >seductive</feeling> when it's about to die, flaunting the dazzle of its incipient exit,
        an ending that at least so far the effects of human progress (<manmade cat="unnatural"
            >pollution</manmade>, <nature cat="weather">acid rain</nature>) have not yet <feeling
            emotion="fear">frightened</feeling> you enough to make you believe is real; that is, you
        know this ending is a deception because of course <nature cat="word">nature</nature> is
        always renewing itself— the <nature cat="plant">trees</nature> don't die, they just pretend,
        go out in style, and return in style: a new style.</p>





    <number>2</number>

    <p n="2">Is it deliberate how far they make you go especially if you live in the <manmade
            cat="economy">city</manmade> to get far enough away from home to see not just <nature
            cat="plant">trees</nature> but only <nature cat="plant">trees</nature>? The boring
            <manmade cat="economy">highways</manmade>, <manmade cat="accessory">roadsigns,</manmade>
        <manmade cat="accessory">high speeds,</manmade>
        <manmade cat="vehicle">10-axle trucks</manmade> passing you as if they were in an even
        greater hurry than you to look at <nature cat="plant">leaves</nature>: so you drive in
        terror for literal hours and it looks like <nature cat="weather">rain,</nature> or <nature
            cat="weather">snow,</nature> but it's probably just <nature cat="air">clouds</nature>
        (too <nature cat="weather">cloudy</nature> to see any color?) and you wonder, given the
            <manmade cat="economy">poverty</manmade> of your memory, which <manmade cat="economy"
            >road</manmade> had the most color last year, but it doesn't matter since you're
        probably too <time>late</time> anyway, or too <time>early</time>— whichever <manmade
            cat="economy">road</manmade> you take will be the wrong one and you've probably come all
        this way for nothing.</p>






    <number>3</number>

    <p n="3">You'll be driving along <feeling emotion="saddness">depressed</feeling> when suddenly a
            <nature cat="weather">cloud</nature> will move and the <nature cat="weather"
            >sun</nature> will muscle through and ignite the <nature cat="earth">hills</nature>. It
        may not last. Probably won't last. But for a moment the whole world comes to. Wakes up.
        Proves it lives. It lives— <color>red,</color>
        <color>yellow,</color>
        <color>orange,</color>
        <color>brown,</color>
        <color>russet,</color>
        <color>ocher,</color>
        <color>vermilion,</color>
        <color>gold</color>. Flame and rust. Flame and rust, the permutations of burning. You're on
        fire. <feeling>Your eyes are on fire.</feeling> It won't last, <feeling emotion="want">you
            don't want it to last.</feeling>
        <feeling emotion="dislike">You can't stand any more.</feeling> But <feeling emotion="want"
            >you don't want it to stop.</feeling> It's what you've come for. It's what you'll come
        back for. It won't stay with you, but<feeling emotion="memory"> you'll remember that it
            felt</feeling> like nothing else you've felt or <feeling emotion="nostalgia">something
            you've felt that also didn't last.</feeling></p>
</root>
